ERNESTO SOLARES

UNITY DEVELOPER

INFO



NAME

Ernesto Salvador Solares Guerrero



ADDRESS

López Cotilla 1790, Americana Guadalajara, Jalisco



PHONE

+52 477 137 1058



EMAIL

ernesto.solares.guerrero@gmail.com



Github / Portfolio / LinkedIn

SKILLS

PROFICIENT

- C#
- Unity 3D
- Github

FAMILIAR

- MERN STACK
- React
- Javascript
- 3D modelling / Design

LANGUAGE

English - Fluent (TOEFL PBT - 610) Spanish - Native

PROFILE

Self-driven Unity Developer with 5+ years involved in the whole Videogame development life cycle. Aiming to contribute to building world-class videogames with highly performant and dynamic teams. Very interested in videogame development (Coding and Arts), VR/AR, Full-Stack Technologies.

EXPERIENCE

AERIA CANADA – REMOTE (2016 - 2022 & 2022 - Current)

Lead Unity Developer for "American Dream Home Design"

(Google Play / IOS)

- Planned, designed, and developed all needed mechanics for the game from zero to deploy by using maintainable and reusable code
- Implemented UI interfaces for the games
- Implemented social features and cloud saving
- Implemented third party frameworks/libraries
- Implemented In-app purchases.

Tech-stack: Unity 3D, C#, GitHub, Gamesparks SDK, Facebook SDK, Ironsource SDK (ads)

Unity Developer for different games from Aeria Canada

e.g. "American Block Sniper Survival" (Google Play / IOS / Windows)

- Ported the games to a windows UWP platform
- Developed new mechanics for different games
- Implemented new UI interfaces in different games
- Implemented third party SDK's for advertising / social features / database management

Tech-stack: Unity 3D, C#, GitHub, Third party SDK's

GAMAGA - REMOTE (January 2022 - June 2022)

Lead Developer

- Direct the development team in the design, development, coding, testing, and debugging of applications.
- Coordinate the development staff's schedule and ensure effective communication between team members and other IT functional areas.

EDUCATION

Front-End Web Development with React Coursera - Credential ID B2WDAE8HNFK2 2020 Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap Coursera - Credential ID CQFCCHLWEAL2 2019 ‡ Coding Boot Camp - Full Stack Development Tecnológico de Monterrey / Online / Mexico 2007-12 ± **B.A.** Animation and Digital Arts Tecnológico de Monterrey / Leon / Mexico

2006- ± B.S. Computational Technologies (Unfinished)

Tecnológico de Monterrey / Leon / Mexico